In this and in the
在这节课和接下来的课程中
(字幕整理：中国海洋大学 黄海广,haiguang2000@qq.com )
next set of videos, I'd like
我将给大家介绍
to tell you about a learning
一种叫“神经网络”(Neural Network)
algorithm called a Neural Network.
的机器学习算法
We're going to first talk about
我们将首先讨论
the representation and then
神经网络的表层结构
in the next set of videos
在后续课程中
talk about learning algorithms for it.
再来具体讨论的学习算法
Neutral networks is actually
神经网络实际上是一个
a pretty old idea, but had
相对古老的算法
fallen out of favor for a while.
并且后来沉寂了一段时间
But today, it is the
不过到了现在
state of the art technique for
它又成为许多机器学习问题
many different machine learning problems.
的首选技术
So why do we need yet another learning algorithm?
不过我们为什么还需要这个学习算法？
We already have linear regression and
我们已经有线性回归和逻辑回归算法了
we have logistic regression, so why do we need, you know, neural networks?
为什么还要研究神经网络？
In order to motivate the discussion
为了阐述研究
of neural networks, let me
神经网络算法的目的
start by showing you a few
我们首先来看几个
examples of machine learning
机器学习问题作为例子
problems where we need
这几个问题的解决
to learn complex non-linear hypotheses.
都依赖于研究复杂的非线性分类器
Consider a supervised learning classification
考虑这个监督学习分类的问题
problem where you have a training set like this.
我们已经有了对应的训练集
If you want to apply logistic
如果利用逻辑回归算法
regression to this problem, one
来解决这个问题
thing you could do is apply
首先需要构造
logistic regression with a
一个包含很多非线性项的
lot of nonlinear features like that.
逻辑回归函数
So here, g as usual
这里g仍是s型函数 (即f(x)=1/(1+e^-x) )
is the sigmoid function, and we
我们能让函数
can include lots of polynomial terms like these.
包含很多像这样的多项式项
And, if you include enough polynomial
事实上  当多项式项数足够多时
terms then, you know, maybe
那么可能
you can get a hypotheses
你能够得到一个
that separates the positive and negative examples.
分开正样本和负样本的分界线
This particular method works well
当只有两项时
when you have only, say, two
比如 x1 x2
features - x1 and x2
这种方法确实能得到不错的结果
- because you can then include
因为你可以
all those polynomial terms of
把x1和x2的所有组合
x1 and x2.
都包含到多项式中
But for many interesting machine learning
但是对于许多
problems would have a
复杂的机器学习问题
lot more features than just two.
涉及的项往往多于两项
We've been talking for a while
我们之前已经讨论过
about housing prediction, and suppose
房价预测的问题
you have a housing classification
假设现在要处理的是
problem rather than a
关于住房的分类问题
regression problem, like maybe
而不是一个回归问题
if you have different features of
假设你对一栋房子的多方面特点
a house, and you want
都有所了解
to predict what are the
你想预测
odds that your house will
房子在未来半年内
be sold within the next
能被卖出去的概率
six months, so that will be a classification problem.
这是一个分类问题
And as we saw we can
我们可以想出
come up with quite a
很多特征
lot of features, maybe a hundred
对于不同的房子有可能
different features of different houses.
就有上百个特征
For a problem like this, if
对于这类问题
you were to include all the
如果要包含
quadratic terms, all of
所有的二次项
these, even all of the
即使只包含
quadratic that is the second
二项式或多项式的计算
or the polynomial terms, there would be a lot of them.
最终的多项式也可能有很多项
There would be terms like x1 squared,
比如x1^2
x1x2, x1x3, you know, x1x4
x1x2   x1x3   x1x4
up to x1x100 and then
直到x1x100
you have x2 squared, x2x3
还有x2^2  x2x3
and so on.
等等很多项
And if you include just
因此
the second order terms, that
即使只考虑二阶项
is, the terms that are
也就是说
a product of, you know,
两个项的乘积
two of these terms, x1
x1乘以x1
times x1 and so on, then,
等等类似于此的项
for the case of n equals
那么  在n=100的情况下
100, you end up with about five thousand features.
最终也有5000个二次项
And, asymptotically, the
而且渐渐地
number of quadratic features grows
随着特征个数n的增加
roughly as order n
二次项的个数大约以n^2的量级增长
squared, where n is the
其中
number of the original features,
n是原始项的个数
like x1 through x100 that we had.
即我们之前说过的x1到x100这些项
And its actually closer to n squared over two.
事实上二次项的个数大约是(n^2)/2
So including all the
因此要包含所有的
quadratic features doesn't seem
二次项是很困难的
like it's maybe a good
所以这可能
idea, because that is a
不是一个好的做法
lot of features and you
而且由于项数过多
might up overfitting the training
最后的结果很有可能是过拟合的
set, and it can
此外
also be computationally expensive, you know, to
在处理这么多项时
be working with that many features.
也存在运算量过大的问题
One thing you could do is
当然  你也可以试试
include only a subset of
只包含上边这些二次项的子集
these, so if you include only the
例如 我们只考虑
features x1 squared, x2 squared,
x1^2  x2^2
x3 squared, up to
x3^2直到
maybe x100 squared, then
x100^2 这些项
the number of features is much smaller.
这样就可以将二次项的数量大幅度减少
Here you have only 100 such
减少到只有100个二次项
quadratic features, but this
但是由于
is not enough features and
忽略了太多相关项
certainly won't let you fit
在处理类似左上角的数据时
the data set like that on the upper left.
不可能得到理想的结果
In fact, if you include
实际上
only these quadratic features together
如果只考虑x1的平方
with the original x1, and
到x100的平方
so on, up to x100 features,
这一百个二次项
then you can actually fit very
那么你可能会
interesting hypotheses. So, you
拟合出一些特别的假设
can fit things like, you know, access a
比如可能拟合出
line of the ellipses like these, but
一个椭圆状的曲线
you certainly cannot fit a more
但是肯定不能拟合出
complex data set like that shown here.
像左上角这个数据集的分界线
So 5000 features seems like
所以5000个二次项看起来已经很多了
a lot, if you were
而现在假设
to include the cubic, or
包括三次项
third order known of each others,
或者三阶项
the x1, x2, x3.
例如x1 x2 x3
You know, x1 squared,
x1^2
x2, x10 and
x2 x10
x11, x17 and so on.
x11 x17等等
You can imagine there are gonna be a lot of these features.
类似的三次项有很多很多
In fact, they are going to be
事实上
order and cube such features
三次项的个数是以n^3的量级增加
and if any is 100
当n=100时
you can compute that, you
可以计算出来
end up with on the order
最后能得到
of about 170,000 such cubic
大概17000个三次项
features and so including
所以
these higher auto-polynomial features when
当初始特征个数n增大时
your original feature set end
这些高阶多项式项数
is large this really dramatically
将以几何级数递增
blows up your feature space and
特征空间也随之急剧膨胀
this doesn't seem like a
当特征个数n很大时
good way to come up with
如果找出附加项
additional features with which
来建立一些分类器
to build none many classifiers when n is large.
这并不是一个好做法
For many machine learning problems, n will be pretty large.
对于许多实际的机器学习问题 特征个数n是很大的
Here's an example.
我们看看下边这个例子
Let's consider the problem of computer vision.
关于计算机视觉中的一个问题
And suppose you want to
假设你想要
use machine learning to train
使用机器学习算法
a classifier to examine an
来训练一个分类器
image and tell us whether
使它检测一个图像
or not the image is a car.
来判断图像是否为一辆汽车
Many people wonder why computer vision could be difficult.
很多人可能会好奇  这对计算机视觉来说有什么难的
I mean when you and I
当我们自己看这幅图像时
look at this picture it is so obvious what this is.
里面有什么是一目了然的事情
You wonder how is it
你肯定会很奇怪
that a learning algorithm could possibly
为什么学习算法竟可能会不知道
fail to know what this picture is.
图像是什么
To understand why computer vision
为了解答这个疑问
is hard let's zoom
我们取出这幅图片中的一小部分
into a small part of the
将其放大
image like that area where the
比如图中
little red rectangle is.
这个红色方框内的部分
It turns out that where you
结果表明
and I see a car, the computer sees that.
当人眼看到一辆汽车时 计算机实际上看到的却是这个
What it sees is this matrix,
一个数据矩阵
or this grid, of pixel
或像这种格网
intensity values that tells
它们表示了像素强度值
us the brightness of each pixel in the image.
告诉我们图像中每个像素的亮度值
So the computer vision problem is
因此 对于计算机视觉来说问题就变成了
to look at this matrix of
根据这个像素点亮度矩阵
pixel intensity values, and tell
来告诉我们
us that these numbers represent the door handle of a car.
这些数值代表一个汽车门把手
Concretely, when we use
具体而言
machine learning to build a
当用机器学习算法构造
car detector, what we do
一个汽车识别器时
is we come up with a
我们要想出
label training set, with, let's
一个带标签的样本集
say, a few label examples
其中一些样本
of cars and a few
是各类汽车
label examples of things that
另一部分样本
are not cars, then we
是其他任何东西
give our training set to
将这个样本集输入给学习算法
the learning algorithm trained a
以训练出一个分类器
classifier and then, you
训练完毕后
know, we may test it and show
我们输入一幅新的图片
the new image and ask, "What is this new thing?".
让分类器判定  “这是什么东西？”
And hopefully it will recognize that that is a car.
理想情况下 分类器能识别出这是一辆汽车
To understand why we
为了理解引入
need nonlinear hypotheses, let's take
非线性分类器的必要性
a look at some of the
我们从学习算法的训练样本中
images of cars and maybe
挑出一些汽车图片
non-cars that we might feed to our learning algorithm.
和一些非汽车图片
Let's pick a couple of pixel
让我们从其中
locations in our images, so
每幅图片中挑出一组像素点
that's pixel one location and
这是像素点1的位置
pixel two location, and let's
这是像素点2的位置
plot this car, you know, at the
在坐标系中标出这幅汽车的位置
location, at a certain
在某一点上
point, depending on the intensities
车的位置取决于
of pixel one and pixel two.
像素点1和像素点2的亮度
And let's do this with a few other images.
让我们用同样的方法标出其他图片中汽车的位置
So let's take a different example
然后我们再举一个
of the car and you know,
关于汽车的不同的例子
look at the same two pixel locations
观察这两个相同的像素位置
and that image has a
这幅图片中
different intensity for pixel one
像素1有一个像素强度
and a different intensity for pixel two.
像素2也有一个不同的像素强度
So, it ends up at a different location on the figure.
所以在这幅图中它们两个处于不同的位置
And then let's plot some negative examples as well.
我们继续画上两个非汽车样本
That's a non-car, that's a
这个不是汽车
non-car  .
这个也不是汽车
And if we do this for
然后我们继续
more and more examples using
在坐标系中画上更多的新样本
the pluses to denote cars
用''+"表示汽车图片
and minuses to denote non-cars,
用“-”表示非汽车图片
what we'll find is that
我们将发现
the cars and non-cars end up
汽车样本和非汽车样本
lying in different regions of
分布在坐标系中的不同区域
the space, and what we
因此
need therefore is some sort
我们现在需要一个
of non-linear hypotheses to try
非线性分类器
to separate out the two classes.
来尽量分开这两类样本
What is the dimension of the feature space?
这个分类问题中特征空间的维数是多少？
Suppose we were to use just 50 by 50 pixel images.
假设我们用50*50像素的图片
Now that suppose our images were
我们的图片已经很小了
pretty small ones, just 50 pixels on the side.
长宽只各有50个像素
Then we would have 2500 pixels,
但这依然是2500个像素点
and so the dimension of
因此
our feature size will be N
我们的特征向量的元素数量
equals 2500 where our feature
N=2500
vector x is a list
特征向量X
of all the pixel testings, you
包含了所有像素点的亮度值
know, the pixel brightness of pixel
这是像素点1的亮度
one, the brightness of pixel
这是像素点2的亮度
two, and so on down
如此类推
to the pixel brightness of the
直到最后一个
last pixel where, you know, in a
像素点的亮度
typical computer representation, each of
对于典型的计算机图片表示方法
these may be values between say
如果存储的是每个像素点的灰度值 (色彩的强烈程度)
0 to 255 if it gives
那么每个元素的值
us the grayscale value.
应该在0到255之间
So we have n equals 2500,
因此 这个问题中n=2500
and that's if we
但是
were using grayscale images.
这只是使用灰度图片的情况
If we were using RGB
如果我们用的是RGB彩色图像
images with separate red, green
每个像素点包含红、绿、蓝三个子像素
and blue values, we would have n equals 7500.
那么n=7500
So, if we were to
因此 如果我们非要
try to learn a nonlinear
通过包含所有的二次项
hypothesis by including all
来解决这个非线性问题
the quadratic features, that is
那么
all the terms of the form, you know,
这就是式子中的所有条件
Xi times Xj, while with the
xi*xj
2500 pixels we would end
连同开始的2500像素
up with a total of three million features.
总共大约有300万个
And that's just too large to
这数字大得有点离谱了
be reasonable; the computation would
对于每个样本来说
be very expensive to find and
要发现并表示
to represent all of these
所有这300万个项
three million features per training example.
这计算成本太高了
So, simple logistic regression together
因此 只是简单的增加
with adding in maybe the
二次项或者三次项
quadratic or the cubic features
之类的逻辑回归算法
- that's just not a
并不是一个解决
good way to learn complex
复杂非线性问题的好办法
nonlinear hypotheses when n
因为当n很大时
is large because you just end up with too many features.
将会产生非常多的特征项
In the next few videos, I
在接下来的视频课程中
would like to tell you about Neural
我将为大家讲解神经网络
Networks, which turns out
它在解决复杂的非线性分类问题上
to be a much better way to
被证明是
learn complex hypotheses, complex nonlinear
是一种好得多的算法
hypotheses even when your
即使你输入特征空间
input feature space, even when n is large.
或输入的特征维数n很大也能轻松搞定
And along the way I'll
在后面的课程中
also get to show
我将给大家展示
you a couple of fun videos
一些有趣的视频
of historically important applications
视频中讲述了神经网络在历史上的重要应用
of Neural networks as well that I
我也希望
hope those videos that
这些我们即将看到的视频
we'll see later will be fun for you to watch as well.
能给你的学习过程带来一些乐趣 ^ ^